welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using kdenlive in this video
本视频中使用kdenlive的教程
we're going to be learning about the
我们将学习关于
transitions and playing with some
过渡和使用一些
different transitions so in the last
不同的过渡 所以在最后
video we made this picture slideshow we
视频我们制作了这张图片幻灯片
have these different pictures that it's
有这些不同的图片
going through we added some audio but
我们添加了一些音频 但是
I'm going to delete the audio track
我要删除音轨
right now so I select it hit the Delete
现在 所以我选择它 点击Delete
key or not the audio track I'll delete
不管是不是我要删除的音轨
the audio clip that was within the audio
音频中的音频剪辑
track so let's look at these transitions
跟踪 让我们来看看这些转变
so if you're on effects you can toggle
因此 如果你在特效上 你可以切换
between the tab at the bottom to get
在底部的选项卡之间获取
between effects and transitions but
在效果和过渡之间 但是
we'll go to the transitions and let's
我们将进入过渡阶段 让我们
just go to like a simple one let's do
就去吧 就像一个简单的 让我们做
like slide so if we drag this slide over
比如幻灯片 所以如果我们把这张幻灯片拖到
here we can put it over top of any clip
在这里 我们可以把它放在任何夹子上
we want and just appears as I eat a
我们想要的 只是在我吃了一个
little yellow of box here and to get a
这里有一小块黄色的盒子 为了得到一个
better view I'm gonna right click I'm
更好的视角我要右击我是
I'm gonna delete this video track here
我要在这里删除这首视频曲目
I'm going to delete this audio track
我要删除这首音轨
here and then I'm just going to click
在这里 然后我只需点击
this button here to kind of zoom in so
这里的这个按钮可以放大
we see of this a little bit larger so
我们看到这个稍微大了一点 所以
it's easier to see okay and then I'm
这样更容易看清楚 然后我就
also going to toggle this so that we can
我也要切换这个 这样我们就可以
see so it fills the whole timeline
看 它填满了整个时间线
alright so we have three pictures three
好的 我们有三张照片三张
clips and we applied a slide to this
剪辑 我们对此应用了幻灯片
clip so let's see what happens what that
让我们来看看会发生什么
looks like if we hit play so that
看起来如果我们按下播放键
picture this slides in we can drag and
想象一下这张幻灯片 我们可以拖着它
slowly look at that and see how it looks
慢慢地看着它 看看它是什么样子
so that's what that slide is doing its
这就是幻灯片正在做的事情
animating this picture and sliding it in
设置此图片的动画并将其滑入
alright if we maybe you're thinking okay
好的 如果我们 也许你在想 好的
well we want it let's we like that but
好吧 我们想要它 让我们喜欢它 但是
look what happens this picture
看看这张照片发生了什么
disappears completely
完全消失了
and then this slides in from black and
然后这个从黑色滑入
maybe you've seen or you've used other
也许你见过或者你用过其他
editing software where this will
编辑软件 这将是
actually slide out and then this will
实际上滑了出来 然后这个会
kind of slide so the other picture will
有点滑行 这样另一张照片就会
be here in the black the black sliding
在这里穿着黑色的滑梯
so I'll show you how to do that and it
所以我会教你怎么做
involves using these different video
涉及使用这些不同的视频
tracks so I'm gonna delete this slide
所以我要删除这张幻灯片
and we're actually going to move this
我们实际上要把这个移动到
video up to over here and we want to
视频到这里 我们想要
overlap these clips
把这些夹子叠起来
about the same length you know I'm gonna
差不多和你知道的我要做的
do I'm actually gonna we're gonna use
我真的要我们用
the third track so I'm gonna go to leave
第三首曲目 所以我要走了
this audio track and I'm gonna add in
这首音轨和我要加入的
right-click and go to add insert drag
右键单击并转到添加插入拖动
and let's insert track above video two
让我们在视频2的上方插入曲目
and it's call it video three so we're
它被称为视频三 所以我们
just bringing video three back basically
只是把三号录像带带回来
because I'm gonna want to layer this all
因为我想把这一切都层层
three of these so we've learned in past
其中三个是我们在过去学到的
tutorials whatever is on the upper most
最上面的教程
of the higher number video track is
较高编号的视频轨道的
going to be what's displayed first and
将是首先展示的内容
the bottom one will be last so as soon
最下面的将是最后一个 所以最快
as we get to this point we have this
当我们到达这一点时 我们有这个
picture being displayed but as soon as
图片正在显示 但只要
we see these two being overlapped it'll
我们看到这两个会重叠在一起
display the one over top and we see
显示上面的那个 我们就会看到
these we can actually see through
这些我们实际上是可以看穿的
because this pictures not quite large
因为这张照片不太大
enough so we kind of see through there
足够了 所以我们可以看穿那里
and again we have a look at the
我们再一次来看看
properties up here we have an effect
在这里 我们有一个影响
already for doing an edge crop to
已经因为做了边缘裁剪
achieve the look of this picture okay so
实现这张照片的外观好的 所以
let's do this so let's instead of slide
让我们这样做吧 这样我们就不用滑了
let's grab the wipe because white
我们去拿纸巾吧 因为白色的
actually has a lot more different
实际上有很多不同之处
options so wipe is basically if you're
选项 所以擦除基本上是如果你是
looking you're probably looking through
看着你可能正在看着
a lot of these transitions you're like
很多这样的转变 你就像
huh none of these I want to do like
哈 这些我都不想做
swirl and I want to do like this but
斯波尔和我想这样做 但是
this has dissolve but basically a lot of
这个已经溶解了 但基本上有很多
the transitions you're looking for we're
您正在寻找的过渡我们正在
going to be in the white transition so
将处于白色过渡中 所以
we're gonna drag it down and put it on
我们要把它拖下来 然后穿上
top of this clip and then we see it'll
在这个片段的顶部 然后我们会看到它
do it - as it'll size itself to be the
去做吧--因为它的大小会变成
same length as however much the video is
视频的长度与视频的长度相同
overlapped and so now by default the if
重叠 因此现在默认情况下 如果
we click on transitions click on this
我们点击过渡点击这里
transition and see what it is it's going
过渡 看看会是什么样子
to do the wipe method is gonna be linear
要做擦除方法将是线性的
maybe from left to right let's see what
也许从左到右 让我们看看
it looks like cool so that did what we
它看起来很酷 所以我们做了
wanted it to do
想让它这样做
right it was very quick - so it just
是的 它非常快-所以它只是
takes this picture and it wipes the over
拍下这张照片 它就会擦掉
the picture above it over top of it so
上面的图片在它上面 所以
we see that's kind of like the slide
我们看到这有点像幻灯片
actually I think we can even do a slide
事实上 我想我们甚至可以滑滑梯
with this one let me see if we can't but
用这个 让我看看我们是不是不能
we got like this o'clock we can change
我们像现在这样 我们可以改变
that to this o'clock one and that'll
再到这一点 那就是
look like this
看起来像这样
we can change so to change the method
我们可以改变这样来改变方法
and instead of applying a different
而不是应用不同的
transition we just it's all under this
过渡我们只是这一切都在这下面
wipe transition and we can do like these
擦除过渡 我们可以像这样做
horizontal lines that people like to do
人们喜欢画的水平线
do so I actually don't do a lot of these
这样做吧 我其实不会做很多这样的事情
anyway you might think they look cool
不管怎样 你可能会觉得它们看起来很酷
and maybe they do this is kind of cool
也许他们会这样做 这有点酷
but transitions you gotta be super
但是过渡你必须是超级的
careful with them because they can just
小心他们 因为他们可以
look make you look really like an
看起来让你看起来真的像
amateur and just like I don't know you
业余的 就像我不认识你一样
gotta be careful I don't I don't do
一定要小心我不我不做
transitions a whole lot but depending on
转换了很多 但取决于
what you're doing so this is how you
你所做的就是这样做的
would apply a different transition if
将应用不同的过渡 如果
you want to do let's let's try this
你想做什么 让我们试试这个
slide again let's do this slide between
再滑一次 让我们在
these two ellipses so I'm gonna apply it
这两个省略号 所以我将应用它
to the top video and then again you have
到最上面的视频 然后再一次
to have it overlaid first because if we
先把它覆盖起来 因为如果我们
if it wasn't overlaid and we just come
如果它没有被覆盖 我们就来了
drag it in it'll just it just make it a
把它拖进去 它只是 只是把它变成
very long so look how long this is right
很长时间 看看这是多长时间
now so this is gonna as soon as this
现在 这将是最快的
video is done it'll come here and you'll
视频制作好了 它就会来到这里 你就会
like nothing's really happening it's
就像什么都没发生一样
just not working right but so to get it
只是工作不正常 但为了得到它
to work properly we hit the Delete key
要正常工作 我们按Delete键
we want our video to already be
我们希望我们的视频已经
overlapping a little bit and then we
有一点重叠 然后我们
drag the slide in and then it knows ok
把幻灯片拖进去 它就知道好了
cool we're gonna slide and we're gonna
酷 我们要滑行 我们要
create a slide transition between this
在此之间创建幻灯片过渡
top video or this top picture in this
最上面的视频或这张最上面的图片
bottom picture and you can't actually do
下面的图片 你实际上不能这样做
transitions between video as well these
视频之间的转换以及这些
happen to be pictures we're doing but
碰巧是我们在拍的照片 但是
they could be video and so now it's
它们可能是视频 所以现在
gonna slide over top of there and then
会滑过那里的顶部然后
we see it like that and then and then
我们是这样看的 然后 然后
the different options for slide we have
我们有不同的幻灯片选项
is where it's sliding so this is saying
是它滑动的地方 所以这就是说
start fighting from the left and then
从左翼开始战斗 然后
end in the middle but we could start
在中间结束 但我们可以开始
sliding from the top and then end in the
从顶部滑动 然后以
middle so then it looks like this slides
中间 所以看起来就像这张幻灯片
over top we could start from the bottom
在上面 我们可以从下面开始
and end in the middle and if we want to
并在中间结束 如果我们想
do a slide out we would we put it we
滑出来我们会把它放进去吗？
drag the slide to this clip here so it's
将幻灯片拖到此处 这样它就是
on the bottom clip now and then we'd
在最下面的片段中 我们时不时地
start so now it's kind of messed up
所以现在开始有点乱了
because we're we start and then slide
因为我们是我们开始然后滑行
well it's just not working but we would
它就是不起作用 但我们会的
start from the we drag this down
从我们把这件事拖下去
first of all and then we see what it's
首先 我们看看它是什么
looking like but that's just weird you
看起来很奇怪 但你真的很奇怪
see what's happening it's like a it's
看看发生了什么 就像是它是
showing the whole picture because
展示了整个画面 因为
because we're telling this slide start
因为我们要告诉大家这个幻灯片的开始
in the middle or start at the bottom and
在中间或从底部开始
then end in the middle so it's starting
然后在中间结束 所以它开始了
this picture from the bottom and then
这张照片从底部开始 然后
it's ending it in the middle but then as
它是在中间结束的 但随后作为
soon as it's done ending it jumps back
一旦结束 它就会跳回来
to this picture so we actually want to
这张照片 所以我们实际上想
start in the middle and then end like to
从中间开始 然后像这样结束
the right or something so this way it'll
右手或其他什么的 这样它就会
transition out it'll slide by sliding
转出它将通过滑动来滑动
out and away onto this so it's kind of a
所以这就像是一种
different way to think about it but it
不同的思考方式 但它
gives you a lot more flexibility doing
为您提供了更大的灵活性
it this way and there's actually
它是这样的 而且实际上
transparency too if we wanted to we can
如果我们愿意的话 透明度也是可以的
have it start a little bit transparent
让它开始时有一点透明
like that and then and then it'll
像这样 然后 然后它就会
actually fade the transparency as well
实际上也会使透明度褪色
so that kind of creates a weird looking
所以这就创造了一种奇怪的外观
effect but that's just an option you can
效果 但这只是一个选项 您可以
have too so I think those are the only
我也有 所以我认为这些是唯一的
two I'm gonna show you today we got we
第二 我今天要向你们展示的是
just did slide and wipe it but just know
只是滑了一下 擦了擦 但我知道
there's some other ones too and and a
还有其他的
lot of these ones yeah we'll play with
很多这样的 是的 我们会玩
some of these ones in the future I
其中一些在未来
actually don't yet I don't even know
实际上还没有我都不知道
what a lot of these ones do so I got to
他们做的事所以我得
learn them myself but probably most of
我自己学的 但可能大部分
transitions you're going to want to do
你要做的过渡
are going to be under this wipe
会在这个擦拭物下
transition and you've got some different
你有一些不同的
options for you know cool things that
你知道很酷的东西
you can create out of that so I hope
你可以创造出这样的东西
you've enjoyed this video go ahead and
你喜欢这个视频 继续
like and subscribe comment and I'll
喜欢并订阅评论 我会
catch you on the next one
下一个我会赶上你的